<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Ananya Renuka Balakrishna</title>
    <link>http://ananyabalakrishna.com/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Ananya Renuka Balakrishna</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Ananya RB 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://ananyabalakrishna.com/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Phase field model</title>
      <link>http://ananyabalakrishna.com/project/phase-field-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ananyabalakrishna.com/project/phase-field-model/</guid>
      <description>Ferroelectric materials possess a spontaneous polarization in unit cells, which can be reoriented by applying an electric field or through mechanical forces. At the nanoscale, the polarized unit cells group together to form polarization patterns (microstructures) that determine ferroelectric properties. Using a phase-field model, I predict how a polarization pattern evolves and responds to external loads. The results are applied to design ferroelectric nano-actuators and energy harvesters. Furthermore, the results motivate research towards developing prospective nanoscale applications from other smart materials, such as relaxors and ferromagnets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phase field crystal model</title>
      <link>http://ananyabalakrishna.com/project/chemo-mechanical-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ananyabalakrishna.com/project/chemo-mechanical-model/</guid>
      <description>Charging a Li-battery, involves insertion (extraction) of Li-ions from electrode materials. This intercalation of the diffusing species (Li-ion) induces lattice transformational strains in the host material (electrode). In this project, I develop a Cahn-Hilliard phase field crystal model, which couples the composition field of the diffusing species with the host lattice symmetry. The modeling approach provides atomistic insights on lattice distortions and defect formations induced by Li-diffusion.
Here is an example of the phase transition showing structural evolution of lattices from a hexagonal (in blue), to a square symmetry (in red).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cohesive-zone model</title>
      <link>http://ananyabalakrishna.com/project/cohesive-zone-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ananyabalakrishna.com/project/cohesive-zone-model/</guid>
      <description>Solid-state batteries are promising candidates for high-energy density applications, like powering electric cars. The battery materials, however, mechanically degrade with continuous usage. This degradation limits interfacial kinetics and lowers the battery power-density. A cohesive-zone model is used to investigate the electro-chemo-mechanical coupling that leads to fracture and delamination in solid-state batteries.
Collaborators: Dorthe Ravnsbaek SDU, Denmark &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Giovanna Bucci Bosch, USA &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; W. Craig Carter  Massachusetts Insitute of Technology, USA &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Yet-Ming Chiang Massachusetts Insitute of Technology, USA</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>