<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Solids &amp; Materials Lab</title>
    <link>http://ananyabalakrishna.com/docs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Solids &amp; Materials Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 12:30:00 +0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://ananyabalakrishna.com/docs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Does electrode crystallography affect a battery&#39;s lifespan?</title>
      <link>http://ananyabalakrishna.com/docs/katex-support/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 12:30:00 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ananyabalakrishna.com/docs/katex-support/</guid>
      <description>Every few years, we notice a drop in our phone&amp;rsquo;s battery capacity. Eventually, we need to replace these batteries, which is not only expensive but also depletes earth&amp;rsquo;s reserves of rare elements. There are several causes for battery fade, such as depletion of active ions, discharge rate and mechanical degration of battery materials. In our recent paper, we demonstrate that repeatedly charging/discharging a battery is another reason, which makes electrodes brittle and prone to failure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What happens inside a rutile electrode during battery operation?</title>
      <link>http://ananyabalakrishna.com/docs/installation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 02:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ananyabalakrishna.com/docs/installation/</guid>
      <description>Rutile nano-electrodes undergo structural changes during repeated battery operation  
Using a combination of total scattering analysis and transmission electron microscopy, Christensen et al. investigate the atomic-scale structure of the rutile (TiO2) electrode during charge-discharge process. They demonstrated the phase-change behavior of rutile as it transformed from an ordered to a disordered state with repeated cycling.
Why do these nano-electrodes amorphize and not fracture?  
On the theory front, we reasoned as to why the rutile nano-particles amorphized (phase-change behavior) instead of dissipating their stored elastic energy by electrode fracture.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>